我向你们保证
I want to reassure you.
你们的孩子完全可以过正常的生活
Your child can haveaabccompletely normal life.
即便是个携有男性和女性基因的宝宝?
How can a baby have male and female dna?
这种情况被称为两性基因嵌合
It's a conditionabccalled genetic mosaicism.
发育不明确的生殖器可以通过手术修复
The ambiguous genitalia canabcbe surgically repaired.
修复?
Repaired?
让它看起来...正常点
Made to look more... typical.
正常?
More typical?
但你连这宝宝是男是女都还没告诉我们
But you haven't even told usabcif the baby's a boy or a girl.
这...得由你们来决定
That's... that's aabcchoice you have to make.
干得好 Jackson!
Nice job, jackson!
射吧
Take it.
本来有机会的 他不敢射
He had the shot. He lost his nerve.
宝贝 没关系 他打得很好
Honey, it's okay. He's doing great.
射三分
Three.
他克服了恐惧
No fear that time.
Melanie
Melanie.
噢 天啊 Jackson!
oh, my god. Jackson!
黑色高跟鞋还是靴子?
Black heels or the boots?
你知道我向来喜欢高跟鞋
You know I'm a fan of those heels.
那靴子好了
Boots it is.
House知道你喜欢高跟鞋
For all we know, house knowsabcyou're a fan of those heels.
你觉得House会从你鞋子看出端倪abc发现我们是假分手?
You think house is gonna figure out weabcfaked our break-up because of your shoes?
那就靴子吧
Go with the boots.
你还要吗?
Gonna eat that?
你吃吧
Have at it.
你拿我东西吃前abc居然征求我同意?
Did you just ask my permissionabcbefore you took my food?
是的 我们可以abc(奥巴马竞选口号)
Yes, we can.
两性嵌合体的少年abc在一场篮球赛上昏倒
Adolescent genetic mosaicabccollapsed during a basketball game.
盆骨持续疼痛
Presenting with persistent pelvic pain.
有趣
Fun.
父母从没告诉他abc他差点就成了他们的女儿
The parents haven't told their sonabcthat he could've been their daughter.
他们希望你也不要说
They want assuranceabcthat you won't either.
趣味减少 但还是有的
Less fun, but still.
居然这么听话
That was easy.
新病人 一半是女孩 一半是男孩
Our new patient. Part girl, part boy.
合起来成了13的梦中情人
All 13's dream date.
在球赛上盆骨开始剧烈疼痛
Severe pelvic pain startedabcduring a basketball game.
可能是脱水
Could be dehydration.
入院时急诊室给他补充了水分
Er gave him fluids when he came in.
可能是长期脱水导致
still it feels chronic.
这个孩子有两性基因abc我们却只怀疑他缺水?
We've got a kid who could mate with himself,abcand we think he didn't have enough to drink?
兼性异常有很多种情况
There are dozens of intersex disorders.
持续的盆骨疼痛可能是abc先天性肾上腺皮质增生症 骨盆肌功能障碍
Persistent pelvic pain could meanabccongenital adrenal hyperplasia, pmds--
这些情况只会出现在染色体abc是XX或XY的双性孩子身上
those conditions occur in intersexabckids who are chromosomally xx or xy.
而不是兼具XX和XY
Not xx and xy.
父母最近开始给他注射睾丸激素abc也许里头有--
Parents recently started him onabctestosterone.Maybe there's some--
"维他命"不会引起盆骨痛
vitamins wouldn't cause pelvic pain.
这儿注明了 要求我们abc把睾丸激素说成维他命
There's a note in here. We're supposed toabcrefer to his testosterone shots as vitamins.
他的父母撒谎就罢了abc还想让我们帮忙圆谎
His parents aren't just liars.abcThey want us to be liars too.
我不会照做 但你们要
I won't do it. You guys will, though.
他只是个孩子 父母觉得他接受不了
he's a kid. Parents don't thinkabche's ready to deal with it.
我爸怕我担心自己有亨廷顿症abc也是这么瞒着我的
My dad was the same way aboutabcme maybe having huntington'S.
这是你的经验
Well, that was your experience.
当然也适用在他身上
It should surely applyabcin this situation.
疼痛可能是隐藏在腹部的盲角子宫引起的
Pain could be caused by a blindabcuterus hidden in his abdomen.
他需要做MRI
He needs an mri.
没错 携有女性基因的男孩
right. Boy with girl genes.
我肯定 你是第一个聪明到abc去检查子宫的医生
I'm sure you're the first doctorabcbrilliant enough to check for a uterus.
可能是阴茎手术的并发症
He could have complicationsabcfrom the surgeries on his penis.
导致盆骨痛
That can cause pelvic pain.
一石二鸟 让你老板甘拜下风abc让前女友无地自容
Way to multi-task. Impressabcyour boss and humiliate your ex.
MRI只能浪费时间
Mri is a waste of time.
执行你的妙计 往他阴茎里置入摄像头
To continue the humiliation,abcyou'll put a camera up his penis.
你是House医生吗?
you're dr. House, aren't you?
我们的儿子出了什么问题?
What do you think's wrong with our son?
这帮人正打算去告诉你
These people were justabccoming to tell you.
你们来了就更好了 我还怕他们迷路呢
This is better. Don't have toabcworry about them losing their way.
我们认为他有盲角子宫
We think that he has a blind uterus.
应该给他做MRI
He should have an mri.
你给他们发短信了?
Did you send 'em a text?
过去13年 我们自学了很多相关知识
Over the past 13 years,abcwe've educated ourselves.
有了无线网络 还有谁上医学院呢?
Who needs med schoolabcwhen you got wi-fi?
马上安排他们的儿子做个MRI增强扫描
Let's schedule their son forabcan mri with contrast right away.
- 谢谢你abc- 谢了
- Thank you.abc- Thanks.
你说MRI只是浪费时间
You said an mri was a waste of time.
跟他们说去啊
So is arguing with them.
加入造影剂了
contrast's in.
Jackson 我们准备开始了 尽量别动
Jackson,we're gonna getabcstarted, so try to lie still.
你们针尖对麦芒的分手磨合期何时才会结束?
How long do you think theabcpost-break-up awkwardness is gonna last?
Foreman和我都很专业
Foreman and I are both professionals.
胃部和肺部没有问题
Stomach and liver are clear.
如果你说的专业 是指他如abc魔鬼终结者般铁石心肠的话
If by professional you mean he'sabca t-1000 build by cyberdyne systems.
真不知你看上他什么了
I never understood what you saw in him.
你看他很不爽 对吧?
He's not really your type, huh?
沿盆骨底往下
Moving down through the pelvic floor.
这是Foreman在他人生最得意时abc给我留下的印象
Here's my impression of foremanabcon the happiest day of his life.
而这是他最失意时的模样
Now the saddest day of his life.
我们才分手 不想这么快说他背后话
We just broke up. I'm notabcquite ready to mock him yet.
House是混蛋没错 逼着你们分手
House was a jerk to split you two up.
但换个角度 他替你做了件好事
But, bottom line,he did you a favor.
肠道周围区域没问题 没有盲角子宫
Area around the intestinalabctract is clear. No blind uterus.
我觉得House有点不对劲
I think there'sabcsomething wrong with house.
他这次又整谁了?
Who's he making miserable now?
谁也没整
Actually no one.
病人的父母要求做MRI找盲角子宫abc他居然同意了
He okay'd an mri just because theabcparents wanted to look for a blind uterus.
既不争辩也不反驳abc二话不说答应了
There was no fighting,noabcarguing. He just went along.
- 这是个合理的医学决定?abc- 他可不这么认为
- It's a valid medical theory.abc- He doesn't think it is.
但他就这么顺着他们了
House decided to humor these parents.
也许他刚喝了杯香浓的咖啡
Maybe he had a great cup of coffee.
或来了一次畅快的肠道运动
Or a tremendous bowel movement.
这只能说明你老板心情很好
Bottom line is yourabcboss is in a good mood.
别疑神疑鬼 好好享受吧
Stop analyzing it and just enjoy it.
我们要用这根管子abc把你的膀胱灌满盐水
We're gonna use this scope toabcfill your bladder with saline.
然后检查你的尿道哪里变窄了
Then examine yourabcurethra for any narrow spots.
为什么会变窄?
Why would there be a narrow spot?
有时就是这样的
Sometimes it just happens.
- 可以让我爸妈进来吗?abc- 当然
- Can my parents come in?abc- Sure.
我以为他们看着你会尴尬
I thought it'd be awkward forabcyou having them here.
他们不是第一次看见我裸体
I have this feeling they'veabcseen me naked before.
吸口气 尽量放松
Now take a breath. Just try to relax.
妈
Mom.
没事的 宝贝 没事的
It's okay, honey. It's okay.
还记得他们让你做的短跑训练吗?
Hey, remember those sprints theyabcmade you run in practice?
多辛苦啊 但你挺过来了
Those were so hard.abcBut you pulled through.
这次也一定能做到
You can do this too.
进入膀胱了 开始注入盐水
I'm to the bladder. Start the saline.
我要到处探测一下abc然后把管子拉出来
I'm gonna look around andabcpull back on the scope.
- 有点紧abc- 有压迫感是正常的
- Feels tight.abc- That pressure's normal.
再坚持几分钟就行了
Just try to hold on forabca few more minutes.
不是那里 是我的胸口
It's not down there. It's my chest.
呼吸不了 呼吸-- 不了
Can't breathe. Can'tabcbre-- can't breathe.
- 他没事吧?abc- 心音模糊
- Is he okay?abc- Muffled heart sounds.
颈静脉扩张
Jugular's distended.
心包积液 用10号注射器
Pericardial effusion. Weabcneed ten gauge on a syringe.
怎么了?
what's happening?
他的心脏充满积液 不抽出来 心脏会停跳
His heart is filling with exudate.abcIf we don't drain it, it'll stop beating
我们把他的心包积液抽出来了
We drained the fluid fromabchis pericardial space.
心跳回复正常了
His heart rate is back to normal.
盆骨加上心脏
Pelvis plus heart.
不符合任何与性基因嵌合相关的病症
Doesn't fit with any of theabcsyndromes associated with mosaicism.
可能是药物 毒素或者感染引致
could be drugs, toxins, an infection.
- 你对这没意见?abc- 对什么?
- You're okay with this?abc- With what?
我们打算抛开这孩子的双性人身份作诊断
That we're considering a diagnosisabcunrelated to this kid being a shemale.
我以为把二者归结为巧合abc你会抗议 但你完全没意见
Assuming a coincidence like that wouldabcusually torture you but you're completely unfazed.
完全没意见?
Completely unfazed?
我像是没意见的样子吗?
You think I'm totallyabclacking in any fazing?
你说我不关心病人 这让我很受伤
the idea that I'm anything less thanabchalf-fazed I actually find offensive.
对此我非常有意见
It greatly fazes me.
- 他几个月前开始注射睾丸激素abc- 维他命
- He startedabctestosterone-- - vitamins.
可能引发了自体免疫疾病abc譬如多动脉炎及SLE (系统性红斑狼疮)
A few months ago.That can causeabcautoimmune diseases like polyarteritis and sle
导致心包积液和盆骨痛
which can cause pericardialabceffusion and pelvic pain.
所以二者是相关的
So it is related.
现在我没意见了
Now I'm unfazed.
给他注射皮质类固醇治疗自体免疫病abc用非那甾胺抑制"维他命"
Start him on corticosteroids for theabcautoimmune. Finasteride to block the vitamins.
你和House上床了
You slept with house.
他拿我的百吉饼前先征求我同意
He asked permission beforeabctaking my bagel.
毫不反抗就接过了这病例
Took the case without a fight.
还答应病人父母做MRI的要求
Honored the parents' request for an mri.
没错 以上正是我的字典里abc对"和他上床了"的解释
Yes, those were myabcterms for sleeping with him.
他的心情很好
He's in a good mood.
和我上床可以解释这个
Sex with me would explain that.
但解释不了为什么我没蜷成一团abc躲在角落里抹眼泪
But it doesn't explain why I'm notabccurled up in a ball weeping in shame.
我没有和House上床
I did not have sex with house.
如果你们两个没有事情瞒着我abc就意味着他有事瞒着我们两个
If you two aren't keeping something from me,abcthat means he's keeping something from both of us.
- 这不是什么好事abc- 也许他只是心情好 天又不会塌下来
- That can't be good.abc- Or he's just in a good mood. This is not a crisis.
没准你可以借机讨回他欠你的钱
Maybe you can get back someabcof that money he owes you.
睾丸激素抑制剂?
Testosterone blocker?
就是说 如果Jackson有SLE或者别的病
Does that mean if jackson has sleabcor whatever that other thing was,
他必须停止注射激素?
that he'd had to go off the hormones?
很有可能
Probably.
那Jackson会停止发育
Then jackson'll stop developing.
就无法进入青春期
He'll never go through puberty.
也许问题不是出在这里
Maybe this isn't what's wrong with him.
也许不是睾丸激素引起的
Maybe the testosterone didn't cause it.
但如果是的话 他不能变成男人了
Yeah, but if it is,thenabche'll never be a man.
我们当年的选择是不是错了?
Did we make the wrong choice?
你不能告诉他这是睾丸激素抑制剂abc得说是别的药
You'll need to tell him the testosteroneabcblocker is something else.
也许这是告诉他真相的好机会
Or maybe this is a goodabcopportunity to tell him the truth.
让事情变得简单一点abc对你们和他都是好事
It might make itabcsimpler. For all of you.
你让我们告诉一个正在生病的男孩abc他不是真正的男孩?
You want us to tell a sick adolescent boyabcthat he's really not an adolescent boy?
这...一点都不简单
That... doesn't seem simpler to me.
不行 你...
No. Just...
给他注射就好
give him the meds.
你一边手臂和两条腿觉得痛?
so you have pain in oneabcarm and both your legs.
现在痛吗?
Does it hurt right now?
不 只有在按压的时候
No. It's when I,abclike,put pressure on them.
你看...这样就会痛
See... it hurts when I do this.
还有这样
And this.
那这样呢?
What about this?
那个手指骨折的蠢蛋是你给House看的吗?
Did you give house theabcmoron with the broken finger?
他们在里头10分钟了
They've been in roomabctwo about ten minutes.
病人该在7分钟前大叫换个医生了
Patient should've been screaming forabcanother doctor seven minutes ago.
谢了 兄弟
Thanks, brah.
我在打点滴 为什么还要扎针?
If I have this iv,whyabcdo I need a shot too?
这是别的药 为了安全起见
Just some extraabcmedicine. Just to be safe.
听说你篮球打的很好abc你打哪个位置?
I hear you're quite theabcbasketball player. What position?
- 控球后卫abc- 小前锋
Point guard. Small forward.
你的运球过人技术怎么样?
How's your crossover dribble?
还好吧 其实我不是很喜欢打篮球
It's okay. Not reallyabcthat into basketball.
会有一点痛
Gonna feel a little pinch,okay?
既然你不喜欢打篮球abc为什么加入篮球队?
So if you're not that intoabcit,why did you join the team?
我妈让我加入的
My mom kind of made me do it.
我爸妈也是这样
My parents were the same way.
老逼我去作出新尝试
Always pushing me to try new things.
但她是为了不让我尝试别的东西
It's more like what sheabcdidn't want me to try.
我--我想跳舞
I--I wanted to take dance.
可她硬要我在篮球和曲棍球之间二选一
She flipped out and made me chooseabcbetween basketball and hockey.
你爸爸有什么意见?
What does your dad say?
他本来同意的
He seemed okay with it.
但后来他站在我妈那一边
Then he just caved into my mom.
你的手掌发红
Your palm is red.
这是怎么回事?
What does that mean?
意味着我们还未能查出你得了什么病
That we still don'tabcknow what's wrong with you.
你说中了 他心情好得出奇
You were right. He is in a good mood.
你和13这样就分手 真让人失望
Bummer it didn't workabcout with you and thirteen.
世事如此
It happens.
你们在一起时挺开心
You guys seemed happy together.
可能这就是最好的结局了abc你也知道她是个双性恋
It's probably for the best. Youabcknow, the bisexual thing and all.
我不会在意这种事
It was never an issue.
你以前不在乎 但以后呢?
No, it never is. Until it is.
江山易改 本性难移啊
This is thirteen.
你们没好上前abc她每晚都和不同的女人鬼混
Before you guys got together, she wasabchooking up with a different girl every night.
时间一长 你觉得你抵得上那种诱惑?
Long term, you really thinkabcyou could compete with that?
House 别睡了 我们得谈谈
House, wake up. We have to talk.
别装睡了 我们不会走的
Stop pretending to beabcasleep. We're not leaving.
House
House.
怎么了?
What's going on?
House
House.
- 呼吸没了abc- 还有脉搏吗?
- He's not breathing.abc- Can you get a pulse?
- 非常微弱abc- 快抢救
- Barely.abc- Call a code.
去护士站拿个急救包
get an ambu bag fromabcthe nurse's station.
他还有心跳 神经活动尚未停止
Heart still workingabcmeans synapses are still firing.
我们必须立即刺激他一下
We just need to get a message through.
你刚刚呼吸都没了
You stopped breathing.
究竟发生什么事了?
What the hell is going on?
我的小弟弟刚刚窒息了 你会心肺复苏吗?
I think my penis stoppedabcbreathing. Do you know cpr?
你的大脑似乎没啥问题abc瞳孔等圆等大 对光反射灵敏
Looks like your brainis okay.abcPupils are equal, round,and reactive.
我没事
I'm fine.
除了乳头被掐紫以外
Other than the fact thatabcmy nurple is now purple.
难怪你要甩了他abc你们还能共事真让人惊奇
No wonder you broke up with him. I'mabcsurprised yours are still attached.
顺便提一下 我在这能看得到
By the way, I could see that from here.
我想那些是病人的检查结果
I assume those are ourabcpatient's lab results.
病人可以等 但你可能会死
The patient can wait. You could've died.
刚刚濒临死亡 却满不在乎abc要么你置生死于度外 要么你早就料到了
The only reason you'd ignore a near-death experienceabcis you don't care or you already know why it happened.
都是维柯丁惹的祸 我吃太多了
It's called vicodin. I took too many.
拜托 有人能说说病人的情况吗?
Can I please get someabcinformation about our patient?
患者手掌发红abc检查发现肝功能及肾功能不全
Patient's palms are red. Lab testsabcconfirmed liver and kidney dysfunction.
我记得你今天没有吃维柯丁
I don't remember youabctaking any vicodin today.
我也记得我没有雇了我妈
I don't remember hiring my mother.
是什么引起小孩abc心脏的毛病及盆腔痛呢?
What causes the enzymes in little boyabcgeorge's existing heart problem and pelvic pain?
你昨天也没有吃早餐
You didn't take anyabcyesterday at breakfast either.
我记得我没有和我妈一起吃过早餐
I don't rememberabchaving breakfast with my mother.
全身性淀粉样病变
Amyloidosis with systemic involvement.
蛋白质指标是正常abc这孩子有点抑郁
protein levels are normal.abcThis kid's depressed.
如果他嗑药或酗酒abc就能解释他的病情
If he's self-medicating with drugs andabcalcohol, that'd explain his symptoms.
搜搜他的学校和家里
Search the school. Search the home.
- 真的? 还是你在转移话题?abc- 两个都要
- Seriously? Or are you just deflecting?abc- Both.
- 你要去哪?abc- 哪也不去 我就呆在这里
- Where are you going?abc- Nowhere. I'm staying right here.
这样才能好好让你们审问
So we can properly discuss this.
- 他吃了海洛因abc- 你怎么能--
- He's on heroin.abc- How can you--
首先 他心情很好 这是嗑药的效果
number one-- he'sabchappy,which means he's high.
第二 当他挪动那条残腿时abc竟然不需要用手协助
Number two--when he moved his bad leg,abche didn't use his hands to support it.
不管他吃了啥 药效肯定比维柯丁强
Whatever he's taking,abcit's stronger than vicodin.
该怎么办?
What are we gonna do?
你真的认为house只是过量服用维柯丁吗?
Took too many vicodin?
他把那玩意当糖吃
Guy pops 'em like candy.
我很好奇为啥以前没有出事
I'm surprised it hasn't happened before.
有没有怀念和女人做爱?
You miss sleeping with women?
你说啥?
Excuse me?
很简单的问题而已
Simple question.
当然有 这也是个简单的回答
Yes. It's a simple answer.
我来查查床底
I'll... check under the bed.
我还怀念和其他男人发生关系呢
I also miss sleeping with other men.
你肯定也不会忘记abc和别的女人一起的感觉
And I'm sure you missabcsleeping with other women.
一夫一妻制就譬如abc你喜欢坚果雪糕时就不能享用其他
Monogamy is li sayg you're never gonna haveabcany other ice cream flavor besides rocky road.
你是说若你一旦没了泡泡糖
So you're saying if you don'tabchave pink bubble gum for a while,
就会立即改吃雪糕咯?
that one day you're gonna chaseabcdown the ice cream truck?
当然不是 坚果雪糕挺好的
No. Rocky road is great.
口感美味 层次丰富
It's a very delicious andabccomplicated flavor.
我也知道如果我试吃其他口味
I also know that if I have other flavors,
坚果雪糕放在冰箱里abc别人就会分一杯羹
then rocky road is gonna be left in theabcfreezer where anyone can just dip in.
可以别再打哑谜了吗?
Can we please drop the metaphor?
为什么现在想起这些?
Why is this coming up now?
Kutner我们分手有个好处abc就是我不会因为一个女人被你甩了
Kutner said the silver lining of ourabcbreak-up was I wouldn't be dumped for a girl.
这里也没啥发现
There's nothing in here either.
看来你看错了 这孩子没有嗑药酗酒
Seems like you're wrong aboutabcthis kid having drug or alcohol--
他啥时候说起这些的?
when did he bring that up?
今天早些时候 就在--
Earlierabctoday.Right before--
今早Taub叫你机器人
this morning taub called you a robot.
这若不是巧合 那么...
Either it's a big coincidence or...
他们在耍我俩 他们发现了
they're jerking us around. They know.
如果他们知道了abcHouse也会知道的
And if they know, house knows.
糟了
This is bad.
不 这是好事
No. This is good.
House只有两种方法处置我们
House only has two ways toabchandle us still going out.
玩弄我们或解雇我们
He jerks us around or he fires us.
他选了前者
He chose option A.
好事
This is good.
但这不是好事了
But this is bad.
"我孤单一人abc灵魂和肉体藏在世人所见的面具下"
"I stand alone,my soul and me,abcbeneath the mask that others... see."
他的胸口还有起伏
His chest is still rising.
他只是在给我找麻烦abc因为Cuddy让我看着他
He's just screwing with meabc'cause cuddy made me babysit.
"那折磨着我的痛苦始终都在abc只当我入睡它才消失"
"A pain that tears and bites "and willabcnot bend. Only when I sleep will it end."
再低一点
Downer.
无关医学...
And medically irrelevant...
你确定他还有呼吸?
You sure his chest is moving?
House
House.
如果他在装神弄鬼abc你觉得你叫他 他就会停止胡闹吗?
If he's faking, you think he's gonnaabccome clean 'cause you said his name?
走开
Back off.
这次只准13捏我的乳头
Only thirteen gets toabcgrab my nipples this time.
重演把我们吓到手忙脚乱的场景abc其实不好玩
You know, recreating the moment when you madeabcus crap our pants isn't actually all that funny.
这么关心House 你真是太体贴
That is sweet that you'reabcworried about house.
除非下一句是 "想要把我的脑子烤熟"
Unless the next anza readsabc"hoping to fry my brain to death,
"去磕点安非他命"abc不然我可提不起兴趣
I smoked some primo crystalabcmeth," I'm not interested.
你不能排除他有自杀的倾向
You can't deny thatabcthis kid may be suicidal.
我们不是来逗他开心abc是来救他的
We're not here to make him happy.abcWe're here to diagnose him.
病因是感染
It's an infection.
他的尿液验出了弓形虫
Swab of the kid's waterabcbottle turned up toxoplasmosis.
用乙胺嘧啶治疗吧
I'll start him on pyrimethamine.
我不知道他会这样想
I had no idea he felt this way.
能介绍一位心理治疗师么?
Is there a therapistabchere that you can recommend?
如果你们和他谈会更好
It might help more if you talked to him.
他还没准备好
He's not ready.
如果把真相告诉他abc他就不会这么想了--
If telling him the truth wouldabchelp him stop feeling like this--
如果这能让他好受些abc我宁愿现在告诉他
if I knew that it would make him lessabcconfused, I'd tell him right now.
可如果她弄错了abc这只会让事态恶化
But if she's wrong, we'dabconly make things worse.
很明显他感觉到了自己和别人的差异
He obviously senses he's different.
他想知道真相
He's looking for answers.
所有青少年都觉得自己不妥
Every teenager feels different.
他病了 这不是告诉他的时机
He's sick. This isn't theabctime to spring this on him.
那好吧
Okay.
你在给Jackson用抗生素时abc能再开始用睾丸激素吗?
When you give jackson the antibiotics,abcwill you please restart the testosterone?
可以
Sure.
我猜House想戏弄我和13abc你们在搞什么鬼?
I get house wanting to jerk meabcand thirteen around, but you guys?
早说了他们没有分手
Told you they were still together.
你怎么知道的?
How do you know?
我每天早上都在你身上abc闻到13的肥皂味
Noticed you smell like thirteen'sabcsoap every morning.
- 你猜的吗?abc- 是啊 还是迟钝了些
- You figured it out?abc- Yes, I'm a little slow.
有人应该提早知会我abc啥时候会被人嘲弄
Maybe someone should let meabcknow when I should be insulted.
那么House不知道咯
Then house doesn't know.
可能在上次鉴别诊断abc你们冲突时就知道了吧
Probably does now that you felt herabcup during that last differential.
你留意到了 可House忽略了?
You noticed this but house didn't?
我想是吧 他一般都会比我高明
Yes, I get it. He'sabcgenerally smarter than me.
- 我们可以走了吧?abc- 他总是比你高明 而不是大多数时候
- Can we please move on?abc- He's not generally smarter than you. He's always smarter than you.
除非...
Unless...
- 你好abc- House 服了海洛因
- Hello.abc- House is on heroin.
哦 那真...是个有趣的提醒
Well, that's certainly an...abcinteresting notion.
这就是为啥他窒息 同意做MRIabc还忽略 ...
It's why his lungs stopped. It's whyabche okay'd the mri. It's why he missed...
本不会忽略的事
things he wouldn't ordinarily miss.
我们做些检查后再告知您
Um, we'll run some testsabcand I'll let you know.
他和你一起 是吗?
he's there, isn't he?
对啊 所以回应有点文不对题
Well, that would certainly explainabcthe inappropriate responses.
我要挂了 好的
I--I gottaabcgo. Okay.
不好意思 会诊
Sorry. A consult.
你啥时候点了这些?
When did you order these?
你去洗手间的时候abc我觉得按理应该庆祝一下
When you were in the bathroom. Iabcthought a celebration was in order.
庆祝你大难不死
To cheating death.
你不喝威士忌? 可以点些别的啊
You off bourbon? We canabcget you something else.
我是来吃三明治的
I came here expecting a burger.
还以为我又要听你说教了
Figured I'd have to endure aabclittle lecture on moderation.
你从来都当耳边风 为啥--
You neverabclisten,so why--
相反 让我喝一杯
instead, I get a drink.
今天我差点窒息了abc还给我上些呼吸抑制剂
Nice little serving of respiratory depressantabcon the day that my lungs stopped working.
你挺好的啊
You seem fine now.
你都不信我是吃维柯丁过量
You don't believe that I od'd on vicodin.
你觉得我吃了更强效的药
You figure I'm on something stronger.
你联想到的全是最糟糕的局面
And because you can never,ever assumeabcanything but the most screwed-up scenarios,
- 到目前为止--abc- 可我总是猜对了
- as far as I'm concerned--abc- funny how I'm usually right.
你认为我服用了海洛因
You think that I'm on heroin.
这就是你检测的办法
This is your version of a tox screen.
若服用了海洛因 我就不能喝酒abc因为酒会导致我再次呼吸骤停
Because if I am on heroin, I can't drinkabcthat without risking another boutof not breathing.
然后?
Well?
晚安
Good night.
还要打针?
another shot?
是的
I'm afraid so.
这看起来像我爸妈给我打的维他命针abc同样的红色盖子
That looks like the vitamins myabcparents give me. Same red top.
这不是维他命针
These aren't vitamins.
是什么?
What is it?
我不能说 你该问你爸妈
I can't tell you that. Youabcshould ask your parents.
你这笨蛋!
you idiot!
好啦 我承认我有暴食症
Okay, I admit it. I have bulimia.
- 我看起来还挺好的 不是吗?abc- 海洛因
- I look good though,don't I?abc- Heroin.
海洛因! House 你这笨蛋--
Heroin!House, ofabcall the stupid--
我没有服用海洛因
I'm not on heroin.
我亲眼看见你扣喉
I just caught you with yourabcfingers down your throat.
我用的是美沙酮.
I'm on methadone.
破玩意 像海洛因 却无法让人飘飘欲仙
Stupid product. Heroin without the high.
没错 它的致死率是海洛因的双倍
Yeah, and twice the risk of death.
可不会被抓啊
But no risk of arrest.
你差点死掉
You nearly died.
今天是意外 我疏忽了
Today was a fluke. I nodded off.
没错 一旦睡着你就会有危险
Right. You're safe asabclongas you never sleep again.
服药过量了 你就会死
Mistime your dose, you die.
多喝几杯 你也会死
Couple of drinks,you die.
和禁忌药物合用 你也会死
Mix it with the wrong drugs, you die.
你想借此戒掉维柯丁?
You want to detox from vicodin?
那也选些不会伤害自己的啊
Pick something that won't kill you.
我没想过戒
I'm not detoxing.
如果你想找些药镇痛--
If you're looking for somethingabcto help with your pain--
不是镇痛 而且消除了的疼痛
doesn't help my pain.It eliminates it.
我的腿不疼了
My leg doesn't hurt anymore.
她罔顾我们的叮嘱
she completely disregardedabcour instructions.
他一直问 我不想撒谎了
He asked a question.abcI was tired of lying.
对于他基因嵌合的事 我啥也没说
I didn't tell him anything aboutabchis genetic condition.
我不要她继续参与我儿子的治疗
I want her removed from our son's case.
很抱歉Hadley医生害你面对这个处境abc但我爱莫能助
I'm sorry for the position dr. Hadleyabcput you in, but I can't do that.
她是House医生诊断小组的重要成员
She's a valuable part ofabcdr. House's diagnostic team.
只要他接手这个病例 她就也要在
If he stays on the case,so does she.
我们得跟Jackson谈谈了
we have to deal with jackson.
不然他会一直怀疑
These questions aren't gonna go away.
他还太小
He's not ready for this.
只能但愿你错了
Let's hope you're wrong.
对不起 以后我会远离他们的儿子
I'm sorry. I'll stay away from their son.
不 你不能
No, you won't.
大概15分钟后abc你就是这孩子唯一能信任的人了
In about 15 minutes, you're theabconly person that kid's gonna trust.
如果他需要有人紧握他的手abc你要在他左右
If he needs a hand to hold,abcmake sure yours is available.
什么意思? 我到底是男是女?
So what? Am I a boy or a girl?
你一部分细胞是男性...
Some of your cells are male...
另一部分是女性
and some are female.
这么说 基本上我是个怪胎
So basically I'm a freak.
不 不 亲爱的
No, no, buddy.
你只是有些与众不同
You're just a little different.
打我出生以来...你们就知道abc却一直瞒着我
You've known this... since Iabcwas born. And you never told me.
我们不想让你不知所措
We didn't want you to be confused.
所以你们就欺骗我
So you lied to me.
哦 亲爱的 我们只是想保护你
Oh, please, sweetie, we wereabcjust trying to protect you.
别 我只想一个待着
Don'T. Just leave me alone.
走
Get out.
我们走
Let's go.
你还活着?
you still breathing in there?
如果是的话abc我让打扫卫生的人进来了
'Cause if not, I'mabcsending in janitorial.
我不想呼吸 但呼吸是身体自发的
I'm not breathing. Butabcit's strictly voluntary.
我应该注意到abc在我之前进来那个男人的
Should've seen the guyabcwho was in here before me.
我听说美沙酮的事了
I know about the methadone.
它是合法的 我有处方
It's legal. I have a prescription.
不管是哪个医生被你骗得开了处方abc他肯定不知道你有上瘾的毛病
Whatever doctor you conned into writing itabcclearly had no idea about your addiction issues.
- 你缺乏--abc- 他知道我很痛苦
- Your lack of-- -abche knows I'm in pain.
我吃什么下去是我的事
What I put in my body is my business.
你一直服用 会死人的
You keep taking this,you could die.
如果我服药 死的人是你 那才是你的事
If you'd said that if I keep doing thisabcyou could die,then it'd be your business.
我不可能坐视不管 看你慢性自杀
I can't sit by andabcwatch you kill yourself.
只要你在我医院一天abc你就不准服用美沙酮
As long as you're in myabchospital, you can't do methadone.
我会派人去清走我的东西
I'll send someone for my stuff.
就这样? 你辞职?abc你为了美沙酮不要这份工作了?
That's it? You're quitting? You'reabcchoosing methadone over this job?
我为了减轻痛苦不要这份工作
I'm choosing lack of pain over this job.
你终归是要和父母谈谈得
Eventually you have toabctalk to your parents again.
不 我不要
No, I don'T.
我有个朋友
I have this one friend.
他是我篮球队的队友 Will
He's on my basketball team. Will.
我们常一起玩 我很喜欢他abc但现在 我担心我是...
We hang out a lot. I really likeabchim. Now I'm worried that I...
那种 喜欢
you know, like him.
也许我就应该是
Maybe I'm supposed to.
因为也许我就是个女孩...
Because if I'm really a girl...
你觉得自己是女孩吗?
Do you feel like a girl?
我喜欢跳舞胜过篮球abc这能说明问题吗?
I like dancing more thanabcbasketball. Is that what that means?
Jackson...
尽管很艰难 至少现在没有秘密了
as hard as it is right now,abcat least it's out in the open.
你没必要再躲在一个面具后面
You don't have to hide behind a mask.
我在你房间里 找到了你写的诗
I found the poem you wrote in your room.
无论多艰难abc自杀永远不是解决方法
No matter how bad things get,abckilling yourself is never the answer.
这是个英文作业
This was an english assignment.
要求我们按照Sylvia Plath的风格写诗abc(美国女诗人 自杀后作品受到关注)
We were supposed to write a poemabcin the style of sylvia plath.
你不是真那么想?
You don't feel this way?
我有时候心情不好 但没想死
I'm sad sometimes. I don't want to die.
至少以前不想
At least, I didn't.
这些抗生素会让我恶心?
Are these antibiotics supposedabcto make you nauseous?
恩 会的
Yeah, they can.
- 我们得靠自己了abc- 他还好?
- we're on our own.abc- Is he okay?
他很好 只是不在这
He's fine. He's just not here.
- 他辞职了? 她停了他职?abc- 她没说
- Did he quit? Did she suspend him?abc- She didn't say.
只说暂时由我负责
She just told meI was inabccharge until further notice.
症状又要多添呕血一条了
So if we add bloody vomit toabcour patient's list of symptoms.
外科说出血时因为胃瘘abc由坏死性胰腺炎引起
Surgeon reports the bleeding was caused by aabcgastric fistula caused by necrotizing pancreatitis.
她一定跟你说了什么
She must've told you something.
不是关于我们救这个病人的
Nothing that would helpabcus with this patient.
心脏 肝脏 肾脏 胰腺
Heart, liver, kidneys,and pancreas.
显然这孩子是系统出了问题
Obviously whatever this kid'sabcgot is something systemic.
Zollinger-Ellison综合征(胃泌素瘤)?
Zollinger-ellison?
或者系统性硬皮病
Or systemic scleroderma.
- Zollinger-ellison症更符合abc- 为什么?
- Zollinger-ellisonabcfits better. - Why?
- 我们至少打个电话给House吧?abc- 可以 我已经打了 他不接
- Can we at least call house?abc- We can. I have. He's not answering.
给病人用质子泵抑制剂
Put the patient onabcproton pump inhibitors.
如果有好转 就是zollinger-ellison症abc如果没有 就是硬皮病
If he gets better,it's zollinger-ellison.abcIf not, it's scleroderma.
Zollinger-ellison症没有更符合
Zollinger-ellison doesn't fit better.
你不希望是硬皮病abc因为那样他会死
You don't want it to be sclerodermaabcbecause that means he's gonna die.
- 总有病人会死abc- 但不常是被你毁了家庭的病人
- Patients die all the time.abc- Not the ones whose family you've ruined.
我不那么认为 是你这么想abc这不是你的错
I don't think that. Youabcdo. It's not your fault.
他原本只是有点困惑abc和普通小孩一样
He was no more confused thanabcany other teenager.
我却煽风点火
Then I started aabcfire and threw gas on it.
你是想帮忙
You were trying to help.
嗨 House在吗?
Hi, is house here?
他在更衣abc我今晚10点再来
He's getting dressed. I'llabcbe back around 10:00tonight.
- 进来吧abc- 好
- Go on in.abc- Okay.
- 她是谁?abc- 我雇她来看管我睡觉
- Who was she?abc- I hired her to watch me sleep.
确保我不会停止呼吸
Make sure I don't stop breathing.
家庭护士一般穿护工服
Home nurses usually wear scrubs.
她不是护士
She's not a nurse.
你雇了个妓女看管你睡觉?abc那简直不能--
You hired a hooker to watchabcyou sleep? That just can't--
神奇的是 妓女比护士便宜abc她们还不会告你性骚扰 哪条好?
surprisingly,hookers are cheaper. And theyabcdon't sue for sexual harassment. Which one?
- 你刮胡子了abc- 那就红色的咯
- You shaved.abc- The red one then.
你有两条领带?
You have two ties?
今天和St. Sebastian医院有约abc商量让他们开个诊断部门
Meeting at st. Sebastian's today. Gonna try andabctalk 'em into starting upa diagnostics department.
听着不错abc我只是过来探望你一下
Sounds great. I just cameabcby to check up on you.
看看你是否还好
E how you were doing.
我很好
I'm fine.
我猜你是
I guess you are.
药物完全没作用?
he hasn't responded toabcthe medication at all?
恐怕是没有
I'm afraid not.
这么说...就是另外一种病了?
So... that means he'sabcgot the other thing?
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我们会开始用消炎药
We'll start him on anti-inflammatories.
如果运气好 能减缓病情恶化
If we're lucky, that willabcslow down the progression.
我儿子死期将至 我却不能陪伴左右abc都是因为你
My son has a death sentence and I can'tabcgo in there and be with him because of you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你找到了份家庭习作abc就断定他是要自杀
You find a homework assignmentabcand decide he's suicidal.
自行其是
Make it your own personal mission.
- 我让自己的感情--abc- 哦 你还好意思道歉
- I let my feelings-- - oh,abcdon't you dare apologize.
好像这样就能减轻你对我和这个家庭abc造成的伤害 他本来好好的
Like it could absolve you of whatabcyou've done to me,my family. He was fine.
我理解你的愤怒
I understand why you're angry.
但此刻 你不该在这
But this isn't where youabcbelong right now.
他不让我们进屋
He won't let us in the room.
他只是个孩子 你是他妈妈
He's a teenager. You're his mother.
这并不是个听取他意见的好时候
This is not the time toabcstart listening to him.
去吧 陪着他
Go be with him.
谢谢
Thank you.
我不是为了你
I didn't do it for you.
我们错了
We made a mistake.
不 我们没有
No, we didn't.
- 美沙酮对他是好的abc- 美沙酮会杀了他
- The methadone's good for him.abc- The methadone is gonna kill him.
他刮胡子 打领带abc准备去见St. Sebastian医院的人
He shaved. He was wearing a tie.abcHe has a meeting at st. Sebastian.
是不是他再买双鞋abc我们就该纵容他吸毒了?
If he buys a new pair of shoes,abcshould we let him smoke crack?
Cuddy 他很快乐
Cuddy, he's happy.
House从来不快乐 只有痛苦与否
House doesn't do happy pain or no pain.
好吧 也许是...但他是我们的朋友
Okay, maybe... but he's our friend.
而这是让他不再痛苦 唯一的机会
And this is his oneabcchance to not be miserable.
高跟鞋 很好
the heels. Very nice.
House又不在 没理由不穿
No reason not to wear themabcnow that house is gone.
- 你还好?abc- 恩 有点累而已
- You okay?abc- Yeah. Just tired.
有个好消息
Got some good news.
消炎药多少控制了病人的硬皮病
Patient's scleroderma is respondingabcto the anti-inflammatory meds.
他的转氨酶水平下降了些
His ast level's dropped a bit.
他死得没我们想象那么快abc真是好消息
So he's dying slightlyless quicklyabcthan we thought. That's great news.
我不好
I'm not okay.
下一次只管承认就好
Next time just say that.
他转氨酶水平是多少?
What's his ast?
185 我记得
185, I think.
这下降得也太快了abc确定是消炎药的功效?
That's a pretty fast drop. Are weabcsure it's from the anti-inflammatories?
还能是什么?abc他停用抗生素有一阵子了
What else could it be from? He'sabcbeen off the antibiotics for a while.
- 质子泵抑制剂--abc- 他又开始用睾酮了
- Proton pump inhibitor's--abc- he's back on testosterone.
睾酮不可能治疗他的肝功能
Testosterone wouldn'tabchelp his liver function.
但可能治疗他的肾功能abc这也会使转氨酶水平下降
But it could improve his kidneyabcfunction which would also lower his ast.
但对被硬皮病损坏的肾脏不可能有效
But not in kidneysabcdamaged by scleroderma.
所以不是硬皮病
Which means it's not scleroderma.
我两小时后有个面试
I have an interview in two hours.
把推荐信给我
Hand over my letter of recommendation.
呃 对不起 我还没搞定
Mm, sorry,I haven't done it yet.
- 你没有权力故意怠工--abc- 我一直在忙这件事
- You have no right to sabotage--abc- I was busy with this.
这是你服用美沙酮必须遵守的条件
It's a list of requirements forabcyour methadone treatment.
一周一次的药物测试
Weekly drug tests.
在我或是护士的监督下abc精确控制剂量和间隔
Supervised doses administered on a preciseabcschedule by me or one of the nurses.
我在别处干活却abc在这里获得治疗岂不是很怪
Seems weird getting my meds hereabcwhen I'm working somewhere else.
对 所以我让你复职
Yes. I'm offering you your job back.
- 我要加薪abc- 不行
- I want a raise.abc- No.
- 更大的办公室...但要在原来的位置abc- 不行
- And a bigger office... but in the same spot.abc- No.
我们都知道你属于这里
We both know this is where you belong.
好吧
Okay.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
谢谢
Thank you.
别客气
You're welcome.
你还好吧?
You okay?
我有些困惑于职权问题 你呢?
I have issues with authority. You?
我们以为你走了
W-we thought you were gone.
- Cuddy舍不得我abc- 你的拐杖去哪了?
- Cuddy missed me.abc- And what happened to your cane?
她出于某些原因借走了
She asked to borrow it for some reason.
病人是死了还是我需要做事呢?
Patient dead or do I need to do anything?
- 他得了硬皮病abc- 不是硬皮病
- He's got scleroderma.abc- It's not scleroderma.
才两天 你们已经得出两种不同的推断
Two days,and you've alreadyabcgot two separate theories.
你回来了 太好了
You're back. Good.
我们注意到转氨酶水平有所下降abc而这并不是得益于消炎药
We noticed a dropin ast levels. It'sabcnot from the anti-inflammatory meds.
是因为他的肾脏由于摄入睾酮有所好转
It's because his kidneysabcgot better from the testosterone.
从而排除了硬皮病的可能
Which rules out scleroderma.
你们两个啥时候得出结论的?
When did you two come up with this?
我们在大厅碰到对方
We ran into each other in the lobby.
有什么遗漏吗?
What did we miss?
当我说"我们"的时候我指的是"你们"abc因为当时我不在这里
When I say "we" I meanabc"you," since I wasn't here.
我们已经排除了胃泌素瘤
We've ruled out zollinger-ellison.
- 愚蠢的想法abc- 为什么?
- That was a dumb idea.abc- Why?
因为它是错误的
Because it was wrong.
还排除了弓虫症 脱水 系统性红斑狼疮abc及若干个兼具两性特征者会有的失调症状
Also toxoplasmosis, dehydration,abcsle, various intersex disorders.
哦 糟了
Oh, crap.
这孩子喜欢功能饮料吗?
This kid like energy drinks?
我在球队更衣室看见不少空瓶子
I saw some empty bottlesabcin the team locker room.
- 但是功能饮料不能解释--abc- 干得不错
- But energy drinks don'tabcexplain-- - nice work.
那么...我们俩没问题吧?
So... we're okay?
为什么不呢?
Why wouldn't we be?
高跟鞋不错
Nice heels.
这一切都是你们做父母的错
This is all your parents' fault.
什么?
Excuse me?
在练习中和前后都喝下了许多功能饮料?
Chug a lot of energy drinksabcbefore, during,and after practice?
你的儿子进来时只是简单的脱水
Your son came in here withabcsimple dehydration.
这是他在比赛中虚脱的原因
That's why he collapsed during the game.
急诊室也是那样治疗他的abc可这并没有减轻疼痛
The er treated him for that.abcIt didn't help the pain.
这就是功能饮料造成的
That's where the energy drinks came in.
肾脏的负担加重 使得孩子需要abc更多的时间从最初的脱水中恢复过来
They put a strainon his kidneys so he neededabcmore time to rebound from the initial dehydration.
那为什么没有好转呢?
Then why isn't he better?
是你们愚蠢的行为造成的
That's where your idiocy came in.
我们本可以给他补充水分abc你们两个却坚持要我安排核磁共振
Before we could give him another glassabcof water, you two insisted I do an mri.
于是我进入了一条死胡同abc只为了寻找不存在的子宫
So I go down a blind alleyabclooking for a blind uterus.
我的手下也向他注射了造影剂
And my team injectsabchim with contrast material.
如果他的肾脏是健康的abc能在几小时里把造影剂过滤出去
If his kidneys had been healthy, they would'veabcfiltered out the contrast in a couple hours.
但肾脏功能不良 于是造影剂到处循环
Since they weren't,theyabcwent around and around.
最后被他的心脏 肝脏 胰腺所吸收
Eventually getting absorbed by hisabcheart, his liver,d his pancreas,
所到之处都造成了损伤
getting in trouble everywhere it went.
你儿子进来时好好的
Your son was fine when he got here.
你们慌张的过度保护差点要了他的命
It was your freaked-out over protectivenessabcthat nearly killed him.
差点?
Nearly?
他很年轻 做几个星期透析就会康复
He's young. A few weeks ofabcdialysis, he should be fine.
你生下一个反常体质的孩子
You gave birthto a freak of nature.
并不意味着要将他当作怪胎对待
Doesn't mean it's a goodabcidea to treat him like one.
感觉怎么样?
How you feeling?
好点了
A little bit better.
我刚才看见你和你父母说话了 太好了
I saw you talking to yourabcparents earlier. That's good.
我妈妈刚问我想不想参加舞蹈课程
My mom asked if I wanted toabctake dance lessons.
太棒了
That's great.
我其实在想我会怀念打篮球
I'm actually worried Iabcmight miss basketball.
因为我打得越来越好
Starting to get good.
没理由你不能同时做好两件事
There's no reason you can't do both.
从明天开始 你来我办公室执行治疗
Starting tomorrow, you'llabccome to my office for your fix.
我不会再碰美沙酮了
I'm done with the methadone.
我搞砸了
I screwed up.
孩子的父母要求做核磁共振
The kids' parents wanted that mri.
我知道他不需要 可我还是做了
I knew he didn't needabcit. I did it anyway.
正是这样才让他患病
That's what got him sick.
你刚刚解决了一例没人能解决的病案
You just solved a case thatabcno one else could solve.
是我制造了这个病例
I created a case.
我表现友善是因为情绪好abc情绪好是因为不疼
I played nice because I was in aabcgood mood because I didn't hurt.
你不需要疼痛才能成为一个好医生
You don't need yourabcpain to be a good doctor.
- 我对优秀不感兴趣abc- 你害怕成为开心的人
- M not interested in good.abc- You're afraid to be happy.
你为什么在乎我是否开心?
Why do you care if I'm happy?
你害怕改变
You're afraid of change.
你唯一恃以为傲是你的智慧
The one thing you have is your intellect.
你觉得如果这都失去了 你将一无是处
You think if that'sabccompromised,you have nothing.
- 喝下它abc- 不
- Just take it.abc- No.
别这样
Don't do this.
已经决定了
It's already done.
你只能忍受这样的我
This is the only me you get.